In the summer of 1976,
a mysterious /mɪˈstɪərɪəs  神秘的/ epidemic /ˌɛpɪˈdɛmɪk 流行病/
suddenly struck /strʌk strike/ two central African towns,
killing the majority of its victims.
Medical researchers suspected
the deadly Marburg virus
to be the culprit /ˈkʌlprɪt 罪犯/.
But what they saw in microscope /ˈmaɪkrəˌskəʊp/ images
was an entirely new pathogen /ˈpæθəˌdʒɛn 病原体/,
which would be named
after the nearby Ebola /iːˈbəʊlə/ river.
Like yellow fever or dengue /ˈdɛŋɡɪ 登革热/,
the disease caused by the Ebola virus
is a severe /sɪˈvɪə 严重的/ type of hemorrhagic /ˌheməˈrædʒɪk 出血性的/ fever.
It begins by attacking
the immune /ɪˈmjuːn 免除的/ system's cells
and neutralizing /nju:trəlaiziŋ 中和/ its responses,
allowing the virus to proliferate /prəˈlɪfəˌreɪt 激增/.
Starting anywhere from two to twenty days
after contraction,
initial /ɪˈnɪʃəl/ symptoms like high temperature,
aching,
and sore /sɔː 溃疡/ throat /θrəʊt/
resemble /rɪˈzɛmbl 类似/ those of a typical flu,
but quickly escalate to vomiting /ˈvɒmɪt 呕吐/,
rashes /ræʃ 皮疹/,
and diarrhea /ˌdaɪəˈrɪə 腹泻/.
And as the virus spreads,
it invades the lymph /lɪmf 淋巴/ nodes
and vital /ˈvaɪtəl 至关重要/ organs,
such as kidneys /ˈkɪdnɪ 肾脏/ and liver,
causing them to lose function.
But the virus itself
is not what kills Ebola victims.
Instead, the mounting /ˈmaʊntɪŋ 逐渐增加的/ cell deaths
trigger an immune system overload,
known as a cytokine /ˈsaɪtəʊˌkaɪn 细胞活素/ storm,
an explosion of immune responses
that damages blood vessels /ˈvɛsəl 血管/,
causing both internal /ɪnˈtɜːnəl/ and external /ɛkˈstɜrnəl 外部/ bleeding.
The excessive /ɛkˈsɛsɪv 过多的/ fluid /ˈfluːɪd 液体/ loss
and resulting complications
can be fatal /ˈfeɪtəl 致命的/ within six to sixteen days
of the first symptoms,
though proper /ˈprɒpə 适合的/ care and rehydration /ˌriːhaɪˈdreɪʃən （脱水后的）再次水化/ therapy
can significantly reduce
mortality /mɔːˈtælɪtɪ 必死性/ rates in patients.
Fortunately,
while Ebola is highly virulent /ˈvɪrjʊlənt 致命的/,
several factors limit its contagiousness /kənˈteɪdʒəsnɪs 传染性/.
Unlike viruses that proliferate /prəˈlɪfəˌreɪt 使激增/ through
small, airborne /ˈɛəˌbɔːn 空运的 空气传播的/ particles /ˈpɑːtɪkəl 微粒/,
Ebola only exists in bodily fluids,
such as saliva /səˈlaɪvə 唾液/,
blood,
mucus /ˈmjuːkəs 鼻屎/,
vomit /ˈvɒmɪt 呕吐物/,
or feces /ˈfiːsiːz 排泄物/.
In order to spread,
these must be transmitted from
an infected /ɪnˈfektɪd 被感染的/ person into another's body
through passageways /ˈpæsɪdʒˌweɪ 通道/ such as the eyes,
mouth, or nose.
And because the disease's severity /siˈverəti 严重/
increases directly along
with the viral /ˈvaɪrəl 病毒的/ load,
even an infected person
is unlikely to be contagious /kənˈteɪdʒəs 接触传染的/
until they have begun to show symptoms.
While Ebola has been shown
to survive on surfaces for several hours,
and transmission through sneezing /sniːzɪŋ 打喷嚏/
or coughing /ˈkɒfɪŋ 咳嗽/ is theoretically /ˌθiːəˈretɪkəlɪ 理论上/ possible,
virtually /ˈvɜːtʃʊəlɪ 事实上/ all known cases of contraction
have been through direct contact
with the severely /sɪˈvɪəlɪ 严格地/ ill,
with the greatest risk
posed to medical workers
and friends or relatives of the victims.
This is why,
despite its horrifying /ˈhɒrɪˌfaɪɪŋ 令人恐惧的/ effects,
Ebola has been far less deadly overall
than more common infections,
such as measles /ˈmiːzəlz 麻疹/,
malaria /məˈlɛərɪə 疟疾/,
or even influenza /ˌɪnflʊˈenzə 流行性感冒/.
Once an outbreak has been contained,
the virus does not exist
in the human population
until the next outbreak begins.
But while this is undoubtedly a good thing,
it also makes Ebola difficult to study.
Scientists believe fruit /fruːt/ bats
to be its natural carriers,
but just how it is transmitted to humans
remains unknown.
Furthermore, many of the countries
where Ebola outbreaks occur
suffer from poor infrastructure and sanitation /ˌsænɪˈteɪʃən 环境卫生/,
which enables the disease to spread.
And the poverty /ˈpɒvəti 贫困/ of these regions,
combined with the relatively /ˈrelətɪvli 相当地/ low amount
of overall /əʊvərɔːl 全部的/ cases
means there is little economic incentive /ɪnˈsentɪv 刺激/
for drug companies to invest /ɪnˈvest 投资/ in research.
Though some experimental medicines
have shown promise /ˈprɒmɪs/,
and governments are funding development
of a vaccine /ˈvæksiːn 疫苗/,
as of 2014,
the only widespread and effective
solutions to an Ebola outbreak remain
isolation,
sanitation /ˌsænɪˈteɪʃən 环境卫生/,
and information.